JASON NAVID IGHANI

C Global Consulting LLC. 41 Central Park West. New York, NY 10023 Tel: 503-330-4354, jason.ighani@cglobal.com, jighani@unicef.org

SUMMARY

Organizational consultant, trainer, facilitator, mediator, and coach.

More than 10 years of international experience in the fields of education and community/organizational development, specialized in working within the United Nations system. Expertise in the design and implementation of system interventions that elicit the resourcefulness, creativity, and resilience latent in organizational systems.

SELECTED PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

C Global Consulting, LLC

New York, NY, U.S.A (May 2011 - present)

Organizational Consultant

- Specializing in learning/performance management, conflict resolution, peace-building, and organizational culture change.
- Delivery of training, facilitation, consulting and coaching interventions in public and private sectors. Recent clients include: Columbia University, UNICEF, UN Secretariat, and UNDP

UNICEF, Performance Management Unit

New York, NY, U.S.A (December 2011 - present)

Consultant/Trainer/Coach

- Assist in the design of a train-the-trainer program (TTT) on learning and performance management
- Deliver ongoing learning and performance management training to managers and staff
- Design and deliver a webinar series for TTT participants to assist the development of training/facilitation competency
- Assist in the design and manage the implementation of a performance coaching pilot program.

UNICEF, Staff Wellbeing Unit

New York, NY, U.S.A. (April 2012 – Present)

Consultant

- Develop group learning material to support staff members in negotiating collaboratively in the workplace, particularly within the supervisory relationship.
- Design training program for the global Peer Support Volunteer (PSV) network to engage staff members in the study of the learning material through small group facilitation.

UNICEF, JPO/New and Emerging Talent Unit

New York, NY, U.S.A. (May 2012 – Present)

Consultant

 Design and implement JPO Supervision Enhancement Program to strengthen managerial capacity in support of improved talent management.

Association for the Sciences and Moral Education (ACEM)

Talamanca, Costa Rica, C.A. (2002-2004)

Project Manager

- Co-facilitated ongoing leadership development training for 30 indigenous organizations.
- Managed curriculum development and impact assessment.

EDUCATION

New York Peace Institute

Brooklyn, NY (2011)

Completed Mediation Training and Apprenticeship

The Coaches Training Institute

New York, NY (2011-2012)

Completed Co-Active Coaching Training Curriculum (Certification pending)

Neethling Brain Inventory (NBI)

New York, NY (2011)

Thinking Preferences/Whole Brain Creativity Assessment

Department of Psychology, University of West Georgia

Carrollton, GA (2005-2008)

- Master of Arts degree in Humanistic and Transpersonal Psychology
- Clinical Practicum: Psycho-education with Latino men in the areas of addiction and domestic violence at Clinic for Education, Treatment, Prevention of Addiction (CETPA).

Centro Universitario para el Bienestar Rural (University Center for Rural Wellbeing)

Perico Negro, Colombia, S.A. (1998-2002, 2004)

- Bachelor of Education in Rural Education
- Thesis: The Development of Moral Leadership Capabilities in the Indigenous Region of Talamanca, Costa Rica, C.A.

VOLUNTEER WORK

Caribbean Initiative

Barbados (July 2009 - November 2010)

Educator/Consultant

 Managed the establishment of community-based service learning programs for children, youth and families.

Townshend International School (TIS)

Hluboka, Czech Republic. (2004-2005)

Teacher/Counselor

Taught Social Skills and Comparative Religious Studies, grades 1-7

- Served as dormitory counselor for 45 students representing 20 countries.
- Coordinated and facilitated extracurricular programs for approximately 90 international students.

Ruth Pringle Institute

Costa Rica, C.A. (2002-2004)

Trainer/Consultant

- Coordinated the development a nation-wide youth empowerment program.
- Provided consulting and training for affiliated youth empowerment programs in El Salvador and Nicaragua.

Mazra'ih Cooperative Learning Center

Conte Burica Reservation, Costa Rica, C.A. (1996-1999)

Teacher

 Assisted in the construction and establishment of a tutorial school for the region's indigenous population.

REFERENCES

Bintou Keita
Deputy Director of Customer Relations & HR Effectiveness, UNICEF
bkeita@unicef.org

Linda Andersson Staff Counselor, UNICEF Staff Wellbeing Unit landersson@unicef.org

John Krister Lowe Co-founder of C Global Consulting, LLC Ph.D. candidate in Organizational Psychology, Columbia University krister.lowe@cglobal.com